This flight is an Indian flight, there are
seats like this, three on this side,
three on that side, then there is a
real fish too, it looks so beautiful, this is
Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj International
and Port Sea Vistara flight, this is
Indigo's 128 3:05, which is inside,
water is coming from above, the weight is allowed
till seven Kms, luggage is allowed till
15 Kms, but the day after tomorrow there is relief around, get up, the
interior has been done here, it is so
beautiful, which flight members are voting,
which are you seeing, this is the entire
Badal, this is Mumbai from no, you can see from above,
how is Mumbai,
all the small buildings are visible
[Music]
Hello everyone, good morning and welcome back to
my channel, today I am going back to Raipur
and I am going to Mumbai to Raipur
in flight, so I thought that
I will share this journey with you too, if you are
travelling in a flight for the first time, then
this video will be helpful for you
and if you are travelling from Mumbai  If you do this, it will be
more helpful for you
because right now I will travel to Mumbai or
Raipur, so I will share with you the entire airport of Mumbai,
how can you reach there,
what all things are there, what all things to
show, I will try to share each and every thing with you,
so right now
I am all ready and packed my bags, I am
ready, right now let's go and
check out at the hotel, after that we will do it, so this
is the lobby, so
this was my room number right now, this is the
lobby of the hotel, right now we are
going to the airport, if you want to go,
you can go by Ola, taxi, train or even by
bus, right now I am
going after booking, because I am going a little early,
if you are going by train, you
can also go, if you
go by local, then the nearest station is
Vile Parle, so you will go till there,
from there hardly a distance of six kilometers,
there you will get auto rickshaws
who will drop you, I
checked out from the hotel and the hotel where I was
staying is  7 Apple Hotel and I have
booked a car, I am just coming, so
when will I sit in it and the
traffic here is very heavy in Mumbai, so it is
possible that I may lose an hour or even
more than an hour, depending on
how much traffic there is, so it has already come,
currently my car is coming
from this side
and I have done it because I had to go
quickly, if I go by local train, it would take a lot of
time and checking a little earlier is a
relief because there will be a lot of
checking, security checking, finally now
we have reached, I mean we are entering
Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj Terminal, here it is
written in big letters,
where it is written Welcome to Chhatrapati Shivaji
Maharaj International Airport, from here the checking will be done to
enter the airport, so we
check the taxis,
then after that we proceed further,
I have reached Chhatrapati
Shivaji Maharaj International Airport of Mumbai and
Terminal, because I have to
go by domestic flight, so
you will get this type of trolley, I was
keeping it here like this  You have to take a trolley,
after that you have to walk here, this is the
view from outside, taxis and autos
all drop you here, after that you
see the gate numbers here, you can see there are
many gate numbers from gate number one, two and three lines
and there is a trolley like this here, when you come then
first you have to take the trolley, then
after that you have to enter from the gate number,
you have to show your ticket, show your ID card, they will
check, after that you will enter, there is a
screen written like this in front of gate number three,
which flight members are voting, right now
I have to go to Indigo, so
I will go to gate number four,
Mumbai International Airport is the
second largest bus airport in India, so
whenever you have a flight, you have to come two to three
hours before because
Lal, I have come a little early, just in front there is a
very beautiful
statue of Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj and the Indian flag
and its design is very nice and
unique, apart from this, this is gate number six, right now
we have to enter from gate number six
because this is from here,
Indigo and Airlines  If the passengers are
entering, then first you have to enter from here.
Here you have to
show your ID card and
ticket, after that you have to enter.
I have done the checking by showing my ticket and ID card.
When you enter, at that
time you have to show any of your
government ID cards and
ticket, you can enter.
As good as the
airport is from outside, the airport is even
better from inside
because it is Mumbai airport. The checking
process has to be completed, the luggage has to be entered and
here it is
displayed on the screen where every single
thing is visible. My flight is
of Indigo at
3:05 to Raipur, which is being checked at counter number M14. At
present, I have entered from here. There are
many other
shops nearby and on this side there are some food
options from where self-checking is available.
If you want to do web checking, then
you can do it yourself from here also.  You have to
drop your luggage, it is
easy to check and Indigo counters are on
this side as well, there are
Indigo counters on both sides, so whenever you
travel in a flight, you can carry only two bags,
one is a small handbag, the
weight of the handbag is allowed up to seven Kms
and the luggage is allowed up to 15 Kms, but if there is
more than that then
you have to pay extra
charge, you
submit it and it comes automatically,
you have to carry the handbag with you, there are
very beautiful plants
inside the entire airport and here there is a watch
and this is the setting arrangement, you
can sit, so when you drop your luggage here,
after that your
handbag has to go for security
checking, so right now
I have received my boarding
class, in it the date and time are
written, which number you have to go to and
which seat is also written, it is
written in it, which gate you have to go to
40 B and the flight
number of this is written as Rahat John and C is
also written as Rahat there is an indication there as to
which side
is the international departure, for domestic and toilets
and here the foreign exchange takes place here,
apart from this there is a washroom on this side and
this is the complete design, right now
we have to go straight from here for security checking,
you have to show your voting card here,
you have to show your boarding pass from here,
after that you will not be allowed to enter, the
gate will open from here, then you have to enter
and here this is the
security checking, here you are
not allowed to take some things in the flight,
so you are not allowed to take that, many
things are not allowed to be taken here, so
you will have to keep them all,
your security checking will be done,
you have to go to these domestic and international gates
separately, so this is
for the domestic gate, right now we
will enter from here, domestic
passengers will vote from here, so
you have to show yours like this here,
then this gate will open, then here  We have to go from here
after it becomes green and look
how beautiful the plants are planted here.
Chhatrapati Shivaji International Airport of Mumbai
is quite big and very good and during
security checking a lot of your
things are checked, your power bank,
mobile, laptop charger, you have to
take out each and every thing and if you have an
extension board then that too and many sharp objects are
not allowed here at all, so you have to take out all those things and
show them one by
one, after that your handbag and when you get
entry, it takes some
time, so it would be good if you bring it, right
now I am going down from here in the elevator
and you can see below
how beautiful the Indore Garden
is, it looks very beautiful, I want to show you properly, it is
more beautiful, there is a
real fish here also and this is the entire garden of Indore, it is
inside the airport, it looks so
beautiful and here people are sitting and
enjoying themselves, you can see this from here right now
we are entering, it is a very
beautiful garden, there is a washroom on this side
and all the things that are on this side  There are domestic gates,
so you will have to enter here for the domestic gates. There
is a very beautiful garden here where everyone is clicking photos. It is
written on it, 'I love Mumbai'. There is
also a fountain inside this side,
water is flowing from above. The
greenery here is so beautiful. The airport is
quite big and a lot happens
inside the airport. We think that only
seeds have come, but no, apart from this, a
lot more happens. Which flight is
going from where to where, what is the flight number, what is it at the
gate and what has just happened, the
status means whether boarding is taking place, whether the gate is
closed or on time, everything is
shown to you here and gate number 40
is here, it is also shown to you here.
As soon as we enter, you will see a
lot of shops here. You will
see a lot of shops. There are
shops for lens cards of different brands and there
is also Wi-Fi facility here and there are so many nice
sitting spaces here that
you can sit comfortably here.  If you want to do shopping then you
can do it in which it is written
that how much time will it take for you to reach which gate number
and which gate number is where, that
too right now I have to go to gate number
40 so from where I am it will take me 11
minutes to reach gate number 40
so the interior here has been done
so beautifully and so beautiful
all the flowers on top and
lights are installed in between it is quite beautiful Indore so a
lot of plants are planted and here
you can also bed, there is setting for arrangement
here street food by Punjab
Grill so this is outside I think so right now I
am in the shopping mall or
in the airport I am confused about this because there are
so many shops all over here there
is also a Haldiram's shop here you can see on this side there are
more beautiful statues you
can see this there is a relief where you have to turn right
now you have to go in this direction for gate number 14
people keep
waiting here and if you have time
then you can also do shopping here there is all the time
here  But cool, if you
can enjoy it a bit, it's mentioned here
that this is actually the
art beat of New India, and if you
see it, it's so beautiful, right up to the
top. Right now,
I'm showing you as far as I can see, but it's
very beautiful. It runs on battery, which takes
you to the gate number in your direction. So,
if you want to
book flight tickets, you
can book them through an agent
or through a third-party application. There are
many apps
through which you can book flight tickets, like
MakeMyTrip, Paytm, MiTrip, and all these
apps. There are settings arrangements through which online tickets can be
booked. The
entire airport is so
big that there are many settings
arrangements here. There's also a walking accelerator here.
If you don't want to walk like this,
you can walk on it.
You can cover a considerable distance. Flights are visible from here. These
flights are from India.  And the one over there is
of Indigo, right now I have to
vote for Indigo, there are some
really nice designs inside the airport as well, you can
see how beautiful it looks here, this is also
very nice
and this one, this number 43, right now I have to go to gate number
40, so I have to go a little further, there is
so much unique art and designs
here, seating of de gods,
so this is the palanquin for the gods to sit,
please do not touch it, do not touch it, there
is such a cool unique designed sofa for seating
arrangement, you can sit here
and there are so many plants inside,
you will see plant after plant inside the entire airport, so
if you are going by flight,
you should come 2-3 hours before your timing because first of all,
your security checking, web check-in will take
time and the
boarding itself starts 40 minutes before the time, so
people
start voting and the on-time
flights leave, so it will be better if
you come early then it will be easy  You
can see that it is the parking area at the moment
and the parking area of ​​the airport is
so beautiful, though it is private
but it is so well maintained like greenery, it looks
very good, but as for the
dustbin, it has been explained in such a nice
manner that you have to put dry waste i.e.
dry garbage and whatever else comes in it in it,
wet waste i.e.
oil waste in which you have to put it,
make the dustbin in such a nice manner, right now
I have reached gate number 40
and my flight will board from gate number 40, so all the
passengers who are going to Raipur have already come
here, they are
sitting and waiting, so
my flight to Raipur is direct from Mumbai, so there are no
connecting flights,
I don't have to change the date, I will
reach Raipur in just 2 hours, right now it is from 3:00 pm, I will
reach Raipur at 5:00 pm, whenever you enter the Mumbai
airport, you
enter from the upper bridge,
I also entered from there, it is very
well maintained.  The airport is
looking very beautiful, so you can see this tap
for drinking water, it
is written drinking
water on it and to drink it,
you have to press the button below, if you
press it like this, water will come out and then you can drink water,
for now let me
show you the washroom of the airport, the
washroom is also very neat and clean, it is completely
white in colour, I am here myself and
this one is for water, when you
touch it like this, water will come out and this one is
for washing, if you do it here,
then you can wash like this,
you do not have to touch this one, there is a
very big mirror in which you
can see yourself completely and can click your photo
and this is the text of the washroom, it is in the washroom in
front of the smoking room and all these people who are going to board are
only for Raipur, for now I
am just sitting and waiting, the boarding is about to start, so
after that boarding will take place, there also your
boarding pass is checked, only
after that you will be allowed, so you will get a glass,
cloth, body wash, whatever you have with you right now  The
boarding has started,
so finally the boarding has been updated, but right now
we are going to board our flight,
and it is like this,
we don't get dropped off, sometimes we
take you down as well, and then I just make you sit and
drop you to your flight, if there is
relief below, and if there is relief above, then you can
reach there directly by making such a track,
this is separate from gate number 40B, there is a
relief with glass from here, from which you
can see easily, this is the kind of flight, right now
I have entered from the side,
and I have to see my seat number, after that I have to
sit, there are seats like this,
three are on this side, three are on this side, these are
axle sized, the one above is
for keeping bags, so you will keep your luggage or
handbag here, and
after that, this seat number is written for us, 15 16
DBA 17
C, such seat number is written relief and A is on the
window side, right now I have
sat in my seat, and this is the seat, there is a
window here,
you get a seat belt like this, so  You are
comfortable sitting with your seat belt on and this
is the window on the right hand side, you can see the view from here,
you are already seated, you have to open it like this,
then after that you can keep anything of yours here and
eat
[Music]
So this is Mumbai from top,
you can see how Mumbai was looking,
all the small buildings are visible,
moving in the sky in the clouds,
our flight will go above the clouds too, it is
moving above, moving
[Music]
our flight is moving above the clouds, the
clouds are looking completely white, it is looking so
beautiful, it is looking very pretty,
I had just ordered Sabudana Khichdi, it has just arrived
and it is written in it
how you have to eat it, it is
ready, it is looking very yummy too, let's see
how it actually tastes and anyway,
add oil water in it, it is ready,
after 8 minutes I have done it,
what you can see is this, the entire cloud is
looking so beautiful, this is it
[Music]
In Raipur and right now I am relieved to have peace five
so you can deposit this bag there
that luggage bag is available in this belt
so you can collect it from here
and they will tell you in the flight itself from
which belt you will
get your luggage right now
we are taking it out from here and this is
Raipur airport so now I have finally
reached Raipur